

# Siyuan Peng

Computer Science Student

siyuan.peng.22@gmail.com

+49 15251479734







### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an self-motivated, adaptable and hard-working person, who has developed a mature and responsible approach to any task that I undertake and strives to achieve the highest standard possible.

As a bachelor student in computer science at the University of Tübingen, I have gained knowledge of computer science from various aspects, also with some experience of projects in machine learning, applied statistics and web development. I am seeing a part-time position in the industry in which I can put my knowledge and experience into practice, ultimately benefiting the organisation that I work for.

## **EDUCATION**

Apr 2017 - current

## B. Sc., Computer Science

University of Tübingen

- To be completed in spring 2020.
- Current grade 1.8
- Specialities: Machine Learning, Algorithm, Web Development.
- Minored in Cognitive Science, including Psychology, Cognitive Architecture, etc.

Sep 2011 -

### B. Arch., Architecture

Jun 2016 Wul

Wuhan Univresity

Completed in June 2016.

### PROJECTS

Jul 2019 current

### Kaggle Competition: Predicting Molecular Properties (ongoing)

- Data processing with Pandas.
- Solving regression problem with Python, scikit-learn.

Apr 2019 - current

### Machine Learning in the field of Eye Tracking (ongoing)

- The challenge of this project is pupil detection.
- Created an dataset of eye movements with an USB camera.
- Implemented a GUI for for data labeling.
- Implemented machine learning algorithms (SVM and CNN) with MATLAB.

Apr 2018 -Jul 2018

### **Web Development**

- Learned various aspects of web development in a course, from frontend to backend.
- Static web page with HTML and CSS (see my website at petra0522.github.io).
- · Client-side dynamic web page with Javascript (online Memory Game, Animation).
- Server-side dynamic web page with Python, PHP und MySQL (quiz game, vocabulary game and Blog).

## SKILLS

# Programming Languages (Proficient)

Java

(Applied in developing algorithms and samll games.)

Python

(Applied in machine learning, neural networks, data analysis, applied statistics.)

# Programming Languages (Familiar)

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

MATLAB

Others

Git	PHP	MySQL	R		LaTex
Photoshop		Illustrato	r	InDesign	
Teamwork		Research	Logi	k	Math

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Dec 2016 -Feb 2017

#### **Online Content Editor Intern**

Wuhan Original Information Technology Co., Ltd

- Collected information from Internet.
- Edited and updated contents of an online shopping website.

### Oct 2016

### **Architectural Design Intern**

Wuhan Optics Valley Union Group Co., Ltd

• Assisted a design team with the 3D model building, concept design and architectural graphic design.

# Sep 2015 - Dec 2015

#### **Architectural Student Intern**

Wuhan Original Information Technology Co., Ltd

- Learned and collaborated with a design team during various stages of a project, from concept to completion.
- Assisted the team with the 3D model building, concept design and architectural graphic design.

# LANGUAGE

Mandarin (Native)

English (Proficient)

German (Intermediate)

### INTERESTS

Reading

Handcrafts

Painting

Graphic Design

Hiking